Shivesh Shandilya

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Over **5.5+ years** of extensive experience as a Front end web developer in developing and designing user experiences of web applications using **HTML5**, **CSS**, **CSS3**, **SASS**, **LESS**, **JavaScript**, **ReactJs**, **Redux**, **ES6**, **Webpack**, **JSON**, **Node.js**, **Ajax**, **Bootstrap**.

Experience in all phases of SDLC like Requirement Analysis, Implementation and Maintenance, and extensive experience with **Agile** and **SCRUM**.

Expertise in ReactJs along with experience in middleware using Redux, Redux Toolkit and other ReactJs libraries like React Router, Tanstack UI, Axios, Material UI, Stotybook and others.

CURRENT EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Mphasis Ltd, Pune.

Dec 2021 - Present

- Leading a team of 3 UI developers in crafting a healthcare dashboard for TRHC, showcasing expertise in ReactJS, Redux Toolkit, Tanstack UI, and Material UI.
- Designed and implemented dynamic smart tables for user, organization, customer, email queue, and fax queue data, ensuring responsiveness and user-friendly interfaces.
- Implemented robust smart table functionalities, including sorting, pagination, search, row selection, and user preferences.
- Utilized Tanstack UI utilities and ReactJS to build the application from scratch, focusing on security through JWT token-based authentication and efficient data retrieval with RTK queries.
- Successfully delivered the healthcare project, providing role based access control and restrictions.
- Contributed to AIG projects, specializing in loan features for the financial application.
- Leveraged Node.js and Express.js to design and implement backend functionalities for one of the projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior System Engineer, IBM India Pvt. Ltd., Pune

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

- Enhanced Tiffany's e-commerce website by designing visually appealing carousels, hero components, and banner components.
- Led the creation of UI elements for new features, emphasizing the shipping details and card details pages.
- Contributed significantly to internationalization efforts, making the application accessible across multiple languages and countries
- Ensured website responsiveness on various devices, addressing bugs, and testing features using BrowserStack.

System Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services, Pune

June 2018 - Jan 2021

- Contributed as a React developer in the Barclays Data Portal project, specializing in small to medium-complex components.
- Key contributor to the RFT Dashboard, implementing color-coded data visualization and robust notifications.
- Utilized Apollo Client and Server for efficient data management, integrating real-time data updates.
- Applied automation testing using Cypress, ensuring reliability and stability of critical functionalities.

EDUCATION

Year	Degree	Institute	Percentage/CGPA
2014 - 18	B.Tech, Electronics and Communication Engineering	Techno India Salt lake, kolkata	8.18
2011 - 13	HSC	St. Michael's High School, Patna	89.4 %

SKILLS AND TOOLS USED

Technical Skills and Proficiencies

- ReactJSCSS3
- HTML5
- JavaScript
- NodeJS
- ExpressJS
- Redux Toolkit
- Headless UI
- Material UI

Tools and Software Used

- Atlassian JIRA
- Confluence
- Microsoft Azure Pipelines
- Visual Studio Code
- Git Bash
- Git Lab
- Bit Bucket
- Source Tree
- Microsoft Visual Studio

Interpersonal Skills and Proficiencies

- Teamwork
- Communication
- Client Interactions
- Leading a team
- Agile Methodology
- Requirement Gathering
- Technical Design Documentation

CERTIFICATIONS